Ekele Steve Ezeala

37 Circular Road Amadi-Ama Port harcourt, Rivers State, Nigeria.

Phone: 07032953816, 09072097303. **Email:** <u>stevanth75@gmail.com</u>

Professional Summary_

Exceptionally skilled and focused IT professional with a superb history of strong technological instruction. Adept at explaining complex technological concepts and theories in a clear and accessible manner. An energetic and versatile tutor who is able to teach across a wide range of Computer and IT topics.

Core Qualifications_____

- Extensive experience in computer use and applications instruction.
- Excellent facility with verbal and audio-visual instructional modes.
- Strong abilities in student supervision to ensure optimal task performance.
- Superior professional decision-making and judgment skills.
- Outstanding written and oral communication skills.
- High flexibility in scheduling hours.

Software/IT Skills_

Copy Editing, CSS, HTML, Python, Microsoft Office Suite, WordPress, Photoshop, Corel Draw, Qualys Cyber Security Lab, Hardware & Software troubleshooting & maintenance, Data Processing, Information Update & Backup.

Work Experience_____

Computer Instructor OLIVESHOOTS INTERNATIONAL SCHOOL

2020 - 2022

No. 157 Abuloma Road, Port Harcourt, Rivers

- Taught Junior & Senior Secondary students Computer Operations & Applications.
- Led classroom instruction in both computer theory and practical applications.
- Guided and supervised student computer laboratory work.
- Maintained and updated student grade and attendance records on a regular basis.
- Provide extensive IT support to staff and students.
- Install, configure and manage hardware, software and operating systems.
- Monitored and maintained computer systems and components
- Keeping up to date with latest technologies.
- Planned individual programs of study to develop student interests and abilities.
- Managed relaxed and rigorous classroom environment.
- Attended various professional development workshops and activities.
- Diagnosed and resolved hardware problems and relevant software faults.

Computer Instructor ROCKCREST INTERNATIONAL SCHOOL

2019 - 2020

Plot 60, Federal Housing Estate, off Peter Odili road, Port Harcourt, Rivers

- Teaching all areas of the school computer curriculum.
- Teaching students the latest computer skills.
- Led classroom instruction in basic computer operation and Internet usage.
- Monitor students on computer program assigned lessons and pushing students to stay on task.
- Provide IT supports to students, pupils and teachers.
- Installing teaching software on computers.
- Troubleshooting PC problems.

Computer Instructor AMAVEL INTERNATIONAL SCHOOL

2016 - 2017

Plot 51, House 63, FHE, off Peter Odili road, Port Harcourt, Rivers

- Led classroom instruction in basic computer operation and Internet usage.
- Instructed students in design application and computer-aided drafting fundamentals.
- Assigned real-world computer constraint projects to individual students.
- Promoted trial-and-error approach to student computer problem-solving.
- Mentoring and training new staff.

Hobbies and Interests_

- Installing and configuring new computer systems.
- Keeping up to date with latest technologies.
- Provided student progress feedback on a regular basis.
- Frequent inspection of computer equipment at periodic intervals to detect malfunction, need for repair or an adjustment.

Education	
NATIONAL YOUTH SERVICE CORPS (NYSC) Community Secondary School (UBE) Eliozu, Obio/Apkor, Rivers.	2020 - 2021
Computer Science (Higher National Diploma) Covenant Polytechnic, Owerrinta, Abia State.	2017 - 2019
Computer Science (National Diploma) Lagos Aviation and Maritime Business School, Lagos State.	2014 - 2016
Senior School Certificate Examination (SSCE) Model Secondary School, Amadi-Ama, Port Harcourt, Rivers.	2004 - 2011
First School Leaving Certificate (FSLC) State Primary School, Osah, Umuahia-north LGA, Abia state.	1999 - 2004

I enjoy reading non-fiction books, solving puzzles, programming, playing piano, traveling, meeting people, playing video games, and playing soccer game.